

Associate seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Web Development, Requirement Gathering, Business Requirement Analysis, Software Design, Core Java, Spring Mvc, Hibernate, JPA, Maven, J2Ee, JSP, Aop, Spring Framework, Rest, Eclipse



Current Designation: Software Developer Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Allianz Technology Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree:

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Kolkata

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Key Skills: software developer,application programming,web development,requirement gathering,core java,spring mvc,hibernate,jpa,j2ee,jsp,spring framework,rest,microservices,spring boot,java,spring,web services,jsp servlets,java

servlets, servlet, servlets

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

I have more than 3 years of experience in software development & implementation, with exposure in JAVA Development at Cognizant Technology Solutions.

Excellent development skills using Core Java/J2EE, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Spring Data JPA and RESTful Web Services

Designed Web Services using REST Architectural Styles

Have knowledge in designing and developing microservice based application which adheres to cloud development principle Have hand-on experience with working on different Spring Framework components such as Spring AOP, Spring Security and Spring ORM

Having excellent knowledge on Design Patterns, Software Model (Waterfall and Agile)

Good command on database languages: MySQL and Oracle.

Comprehensive knowledge of SDLC with proficiency in mapping of business requirements, technical documentation, custom designing solutions, development & troubleshooting for complex software & application problems

Work Experience

Allianz Technology as Software Developer Aug 2020 to Till Date

Cognizant Technologies Solutions as Associate -IT

Jan 2016 to Aug 2019

Project 1 Client: A global biopharmaceutical company

Description The objective of the project was to use Reltio (which is a cloudbased MDM tool) as a platform for storing different material types and manage the approval process for creating and updating materials within the system.

Duration Feb, 2019 - August, 2019

Responsibilities * Interacting with client-base/onsite counterparts to collect, analyze and study requirements.

* Worked in various REST API calls, json integration, File Handling in java to perform activities like business validation during data load and entity creation from UI, creating/updating new entity based on the business requirement.

Project 2 Client: A global biopharmaceutical company

Description The objective of the project was to use Reltio (a cloud-based MDM tool) to

provide the client a 360-degree view of its customer data and publish golden copy of the data that was clean, standardized and free of duplicates.

Duration June, 2017- January, 2019

Responsibilities Developed code for the Data Load Utility module load the data and retrieve the data from Reltio tenant by utilizing Reltio data load APIs.

- I was responsible for developing tools for the ETL (extract, transform and load)
- layer and writing codes for business validation at different stages of the load process.
- Defined and configured various MDM process including match and merge and survivorship rules to de-duplicate records in the data to ensure data quality.
- Wrote SQL scripts for data transformation to generate the Common Format Files (CFF) from the Source Data.

Project 3 Client: A high-end retail company

The aim was to create a Master Data Management solution using Stibo STEP Description

tool to collect and merge product information under one repository along with their associations and hierarchies, and to design a portal where vendors can create and maintain item information

January,2016-May,2017 Duration

Responsibilities Communicated with business customers to discuss the requirements and based on requirements, designed and implemented STEP JavaScript Business Rules.

- Was responsible for deploying the developed code in the production and testing environments through UNIX server.
- Provided support with regards to working towards issue reproduction and root cause analysis in critical issues in system and implemented fixes.
- Monitored everyday inbound and outbound batch process failures, collaborated with other teams to investigate the cause, and provided fix for the same to ensure that data across all systems are aligned.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from KIIT UNIVERSITY in 2015

PG: in 0

IT Skills

| Skill Name | Version Last Us | sed Experience |
|---------------------------------|-----------------|----------------------|
| Java, J2EE (JSP, Servlet, JDBC) | 8 | 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s) |
| SPRING MVC | 5 | 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s) |
| ORACLE 11g, MySQL | | |
| Eclipse, Web logic | | |
| SQL Developer, Putty | | |
| Maven, Postman Client | | |
| SPRING FRAMEWORK | 5 0 | 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s) |
| spring boot | 0 | 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s) |
| JAVA | 0 | 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s) |
| CORE JAVA | 0 | 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s) |

Languages Known

| Language | Proficiency | Read | Write | Speak |
|----------|-------------|------|-------|-------|
| English | | | | |
| Hindi | | | | |

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

1/22/2021 Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time